Register of the Louis Kahlenberg Papers, 1900-1939
Wisconsin Historical Society
Louis Kahlenberg Papers, 1900-1939
Kahlenberg, Louis, 1870-1941
Wis Mss LS
2.4 c.f. (12 archives boxes)
Wisconsin Historical Society, Library-Archives Division
Correspondence of Louis Kahlenberg, a member of the department of chemistry of the University of Wisconsin and for eleven years its chairman, dealing with problems of research, administration, publications, and placement of students through a period of important development in scientific studies and methods. Also present is a transcription of a family record page (1868-1927) from a family Bible.
Papers of Kahlenberg, a member of the faculty of the University of Wisconsin chemistry department, 1895-1940, and department chairman, 1908-1919. Eleven boxes of correspondence with scientists, the university graduate school, university business office, and industrial concerns deals with technical chemical questions, problems, analyses, projects, theories, and research, with matters of departmental administration, professional publications, speaking engagements, and industrial and pedagogical placements. There is also a box of addresses and articles on technical subjects, including a sketch of President Charles Kendall Adams as Kahlenberg knew him during his first years of teaching at Wisconsin.
Administrative/Restriction Information
Presented by Mrs. Louis Kahlenberg, September 1941.
Contents List
- Correspondence
  - 1900, March-1902, April (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 1903, August-1905, October (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 1906, April-December (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 1907, January-1908, December (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 1909, January-December (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 1910, January-May (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - 1910, June-August (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - 1910, September-December (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 1911, January-February (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - 1911, March-April (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - 1911, May-June (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - 1911, August-October (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - 1911, November (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - 1912, January-April (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - 1912, May-July (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - 1912, September-December (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - 1913, January-March (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - 1913, April-September (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - 1913, October-December (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - 1914, January-April (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - 1914, May-June (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - 1914, July-October (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - 1914, November-December (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - 1915, January-March (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - 1915, April-August (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - 1915, September-December (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - 1916, January-March (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - 1916, April-September (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - 1916, October-1918, March (Box 5)
  - 1918, April-May (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - 1918, June-July (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - 1918, August-September (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - 1918, October-December (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - 1919, January-February (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - 1919, March-August (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - 1919, September-October (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - 1919, November-December (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - 1920, January-March (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - 1920, April-August (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - 1920, September-December (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - 1921, January-1922, May (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - 1922, June-August (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - 1922, September-October (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - 1922, November-December (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - 1923, January-February (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - 1923, March-May (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - 1923, June-September (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - 1923, October-December (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - 1924, January-April (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - 1924, May-September (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - 1924, October-December (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - 1925, January-March (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - 1925, April-December (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - 1926, January-1929, March (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - 1929, May-October (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - 1929, November-December (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - 1930, January-February (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - 1930, March-April (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - 1930, May-July (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - 1930, August-November (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - 1930, December-1931, January (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - 1931, February-March (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - 1931, April-May (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - 1931, June-September (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - 1931, October-December (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - 1932, December-1933, October (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - 1933, November-1939, June; undated (Box 11, Folder 7)
- Articles and Addresses
  - Sketch of Charles K. Adams (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Articles (Box 12, Folder 2-5)
- Typewritten record of Family Register in Bible which belonged to the Kahlenberg family (Box 12, Folder 6)